Luke Floden

Senior Fullstack Software Engineer

luke.floden@gmail.com • 502-498-7818 ••• lukefloden.me • linkedin.com/in/luke-floden

CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 5+ years with startups in the healthcare and sustainability sectors

Skill Highlight 3+ years building web applications with React/Laravel

Leadership Project lead of distributed teams and mentoring junior developers

Languages Typescript, React, SvelteKit, Laravel Tools Sentry, Fly.io, Vercel, AWS, GCP

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cadence OneFive

New York, NY

Lead Software Engineer

05/2024 - 11/2024

Technologies: Laravel, Livewire, Alpine.js, Vite, Tailwind

- Led development team of 4 across 5 time-zones
 - Introduced weekly demos with stakeholders, re-aligning a project already 50% past its original timeline
- Responsible for site-wide UI design overhaul
 - Reduced 1000s of lines of copy-pasted code
 - Increased mobile support: Improving functionality and readability across 5 screen sizes
 - Fixed broken accessibility features: Loading/focus styles, keyboard navigation, fixing incorrect HTML
- Upgraded an aging, monolithic codebase
 - Saved 5+ developer hours weekly by transitioning from Webpack to Vite.
 - Eliminated source of frequent bugs: fixing component lifecycle management with an upgrade to Livewire 3
- Introduced automated linting/formatting to front and back end
 - Surfaced 20+ pages with broken HTML: addressing long-standing UI bugs
 - Reduced time spent on code reviews by reducing lines changed by 50%

Senior Software Engineer (contract)

02/2024 - 05/2024

- Led redesign of primary user flow
 - Optimized navigation UX: Providing <100ms response times to user's input (INP Core Web Vital)
 - Brought cohesion to the design system, implementing changes in Figma
- Co-led (with CEO) the process of acquiring a UI designer: Responsible for ultimate hiring decision.
- Identified shortcomings of team management and took on lead/PM role with promotion.

Curai Health

Palo Alto, CA

Software Engineer III

09/2022 - 06/2023

Technologies: React (Native), TanStack, Redux, FastAPI, Flask

- Developed cross-platform apps with over 20,000 downloads
 - Owned payment/paywall features: Planning, design, implementation, and A/B testing
 - Reduced redundant data fetching by 50+% by replacing Redux with TanStack Query
- Designed/implemented external typescript SDK+API
 - Minimally invasive to main product: utilizing cross-document messaging and custom routing

Software Engineer II

09/2021 - 09/2022

- Designed and Created an authenticated business-partner portal; with instant validation and user feedback
 - Integrated with Slack: aiding growth team in prompt outreach
- Kicked off a project for an external gateway service: managing gradual migration to microservices across 4 development teams
 - Championed Automated documentation and endpoint data type-safety through FastAPI
- Developed an interactive data analysis tool for machine learning model pipelines (React + dc.js)
 - Early detection of bias and safeguards surrounding the demographics of our users.

EDUCATION, ACCREDITATIONS, & HONORS

University of Louisville: J.B. Speed School of Engineering

2021

Masters of Engineering in Computer Science Engineering